aat.org.uk 2017-06-06

# AAT privacy policy | AAT

AAT carries a firm commitment to the privacy of your personal data.

This privacy policy describes the information we collect through this website ([www.aat.org.uk](http://www.aat.org.uk/)), and:

  * What we do with it
  * Who we share parts of it with
  * The information we collect and how we use it.

We believe it is essential to respect the privacy of all visitors and to make safe and ethical use of the information provided to the website. We aim to give you as much control as possible over the information you give us, and in all cases the disclosure of your personal details is voluntary.

Where we ask for information we do so in order to offer you better services, both on the website and in the rest of our operations.

If you believe that any information we hold about you is inaccurate, you can update your details in your MyAAT account or contact us to update it.

Some of the information you give will be held in databases: we ensure that these are highly secure and can only be accessed by authorised people.

We will ask for your email address to:

  * Set up your MyAAT account
  * Update you with information and newsletters relevant to your studies and membership
  * Send you occasional invitations to participate in surveys to help us enhance and improve our service.

You can change your email address or choose not to receive further information at any time.

## Who will have access to the information

Any information you give will be available to AAT. We will never share your email address with third parties except select parties we commission to undertake research on our behalf. 

We will only allow trusted and relevant organisations to contact you, where we believe you will be interested in the information they can provide. Your contact details will not be provided directly to the third party organisation but to an independent mailing house who will then delete your details from their database as part of the Data Protection Act 1998. The information you’ll receive from third party organisations will be related to your AAT studies, CPD opportunities, career or study progression

Information you give in response to surveys and questionnaires on the website will be used in two ways:

  * By AAT itself to help determine policy and to help improve its services to members
  * By third parties that AAT may make the information available for market research - in this case, the information will be made available only in the form of anonymous qualitative and statistical reports.

We may follow up some survey responses by phone or email, but only where you have given your permission for us to do so as part of the initial research.

## Booking AAT events

You can book to attend AAT events through a third party site which is managed by Eventsforce. 

  Eventsforce Solutions Ltd is registered with the Information Commissioner under the Data Protection Act 1998. The company, on behalf of its customers, takes all reasonable steps necessary to ensure that all personal data held on any of its systems – including the events management system “Eventsforce” – is kept secure against unauthorised access, loss or destruction.

  AAT will have access to all the data shared by event attendees. No identifying information will ever be passed or sold to a third party.

The website [www.aat.org.uk](http://www.aat.org.uk/) is a completely separate entity to Eventsforce booking platform. If you book on an AAT event, we will email you from the Eventsforce platform about your booking. 

## AAT Green Room

AAT Green Room is an online research community that is set up to gather valuable insights and feedback from AAT students, professional members and individuals that have a relationship with AAT. Each month we will give participants the opportunity to share their views via surveys, instant polls and open questions. This information will help us improve our operations and services.

We will have access to all data shared by participants each month in AAT Green Room. All feedback is confidential and for the use by AAT only. No identifying participant information will ever be passed or sold to a third party.

AAT Green Room is hosted by a separate organisation, Vision Critical, on a separate platform [www.aatgreenroom.org](http://www.aatgreenroom.org/)

The website [www.aat.org.uk](http://www.aat.org.uk/) is a completely separate entity to AAT Green Room. Participants can unsubscribe from a community through the unsubscribe link provided at the footer of every email from the community or through the AAT Green Room Portal by clicking on 'My Profile' and clicking on the 'Unsubscribe' button at the bottom of the page.

## Technical information

Like most websites, our server gathers limited information about you during a session, including the IP address and domain name from which you are accessing the server and your browser configuration. This information is only used to help us improve the content, design and performance of the site, and is not linked to the identity of any individual user.

Our site uses cookies. Cookies are small pieces of information that are transferred to and stored by your browser on your computer.

In no circumstances do we collect any data that is not directly related to the use of the website (for example, we do not record other sites that you have visited).

The log files or any information they contain about your use of the site will not be made available to any third parties other than as anonymous usage statistics.

Our site uses the following two Google Analytics advertising features:

  * DoubleClick platform integration
  * Demographics and interest reporting.

Google Analytics collects data about our site’s traffic via the use of Google advertising cookies. We will never match any personally identifiable information with non-personally identifiable information through the use of these Google Advertising features. You can [opt out of the use of Google Analytics advertising features](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) if you wish.

## Other websites

The website contains external links to other sites. AAT is not responsible for the privacy policies, content or practices of these sites.

## Data Protection Act

This privacy statement forms part of AAT's commitment to the principles of the Data Protection Act 1998.

If you wish to exercise your rights of access to your personal data processed by AAT then please contact the co-ordinator in writing at the address below:

Data Protection  
AAT

140 Aldersgate Street

London

EC1A 4HY

## General

The terms and conditions contained in this legal notice shall be governed by English law. You may access the website from anywhere in the world; however, this legal notice shall apply regardless of how you access the website and from where.

A company limited by guarantee (NO. 1518983) and registered as a charity (NO. 1050724)

Registered in England and Wales, Registered Office:  
140 Aldersgate Street London EC1A 4HY

AAT is security accredited by [Cyber Essentials Plus](https://www.cyberstreetwise.com/cyberessentials/). Cyber Essentials is a  Government-backed and industry supported scheme to guide businesses in protecting themselves against cyber threats.
